(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-29T02:16:51.477961",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
鷹嶺ルイ 重大告知 LIVE
Takane Lui - Important Announcement LIVE
ホロライブ秘密結社holoX 鷹嶺ルイ 幹部
Hololive Secret Society holoX - Executive Takane Lui
3D LIVE
重大告知 LIVE
Important Announcement LIVE
NEXT CHAPTER: LAPIS LAZULI
holoX Executives - Takane Lui 3D LIVE
Lapis Lazuli - 鷹嶺ルイ 重大告知 LIVE
Lapis Lazuli - Takane Lui Important Announcement LIVE
死の国 地中 海の境界に乗っかって
On the border of the underworld, the earth, and the sea,
面倒くささを押し付けられてる
I'm being forced to deal with all the troubles
何から何まで
from top to bottom.
私語は止めて また脈絡なきを聞くお上手に
Stop the whispering, and nodding along skillfully
うなずき合える
to things with no connection.
泣き伏し凝らして
Crying face down, holding it in.
さあ だだだだ 黙れ 黙り黙れよ
Now, s-s-s-shut up, shut up and stay quiet!
言えないないない そんな強い言葉は
I can't say, say, say such harsh words.
屈した気 静かにしてほしいねえ あー
To those who feel defeated, I want you to be quiet, ah~
私たち大防衛
We are on the grand defense!
世界てんてんでぷくややや
The world is dotted with swelling points, yah-yah-yah,
果たすその日まで
until the day we fulfill it.
らんらんらんぷくややや
Ran-ran-ran, swelling up, yah-yah-yah,
あなたの周りもややや
even around you, yah-yah-yah.
せいせいせいぷくややや
Sei-sei-sei, swelling up, yah-yah-yah,
約束の地まで
All the way to the promised land.
さあ 掻き毟るバッテン バッテン
Now, scratching a cross, a cross,
てん てん てん ぷく や や や
dot, dot, dot, swelling up, yah-yah-yah!
今日も綺麗 そっちのけだね
Beautiful today as well, completely ignored.
遺恨になるから私一人でもやっておきますね
Since it'll cause a grudge, I'll just do it on my own.
全て全て全て任せて それをさせてよ
Leave everything, everything, everything to me, let me do it!
私のことなの 分かっているでしょう
It's about me, you already know that, right?
死の国 地中 海の境界に乗っかって
On the border of the underworld, the earth, and the sea,
面倒くさいまま今日も明日も過ぎて行くのでしょう
it'll probably keep passing by today and tomorrow in this troublesome way.
みんな来てくれてありがとう！
Everyone, thank you so much for coming!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
一緒に歌って！
Sing along with us!
歌って！
Sing it!
嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
花瓶に水をあげましょう
Let's water the vase.
時折の 枯れ折れたこと忘れてた
I had forgotten about the occasional withered and broken pieces.
さあ だだだだ 黙れ 黙り黙れよ
Now, s-s-s-shut up, shut up and stay quiet!
言えないないない そんな強い言葉は
I can't say, say, say such harsh words.
少しだけ静かにしてほしいねえ あー
I want things to be just a little quiet, yeah, ah~
私たち大防衛
We are on the grand defense!
今と未来 見ていたかったはずなのに
Even though we were supposed to want to see the present and the future...
世界てんてんでぷくややや
The world is dotted with swelling points, yah-yah-yah,
見えぬその日まで
until that unseen day.
とととととややや
To-to-to-to-to, yah-yah-yah,
この世の理ややや
the laws of this world, yah-yah-yah.
今はせいせいせいぷくさささ
Now it's sei-sei-sei, swelling up, sah-sah-sah,
あなたの街中
all over your town.
形作るバッテン
Forming a cross,
さあ世界てんてんでぷくややや
now the world is dotted with swelling points, yah-yah-yah!
果たすその日まで
Until the day we fulfill it!
らんらんらんぷくややや
Ran-ran-ran, swelling up, yah-yah-yah,
あなたの周りもややや
even around you, yah-yah-yah.
せいせいせいぷくややや
Sei-sei-sei, swelling up, yah-yah-yah,
約束の地まで
all the way to the promised land.
さあ 掻き毟るバッテン バッテン
Now, scratching a cross, a cross,
てん てん てん ぷく 知らして
dot, dot, dot, swelling up, let them know!
一時の愛を分けましょう
Let's share a momentary love.
もういいじゃんムキになっちゃって
Isn't it enough? Getting so worked up,
カッコつけてカッコよくない
trying to look cool, but it's not cool at all.
そういうの嫌になってるんだ
I'm getting sick of that kind of stuff.
ほっといてよ 死にたくない
Leave me alone, I don't want to die.
もういいじゃん やけになってんの
Isn't it enough? Are you getting desperate?
嫉トしたり じっとできない
Being jealous, unable to stay still.
聞こえないよう耳塞いだって
Even if I plug my ears so I can't hear,
言ってくるじゃん しんどいな
they keep telling me anyway, it's so exhausting.
僕は誰も覗かないよ
I don't peek into anyone's life,
だから僕のことそっとしておいて
so please just leave me alone.
うざいだけのバカに はいはいはい
To the annoying idiots: "Yeah, yeah, yeah."
受ける またのお越し待ってるね ととか
"So funny, I'm looking forward to your next visit," or whatever.
本当は怯えてる 吠えるだけの弱虫だった
The truth is, I was just a frightened coward who only knows how to bark.
痛いくせに耐えて はいはいはい
Enduring it even though it hurts: "Yeah, yeah, yeah."
いつも平気なフリばっかなの
I'm always just pretending to be fine.
僕は壁を張ったまま笑う
I smile while keeping my walls up,
それ以上近づかないで 怖いじゃん
don't come any closer, it's scary.
ばかばっか
Idiots everywhere.
やだ ばかばっか
No, they're all just idiots.
もういいじゃん まだ怒ってんの
Isn't it enough? Are you still angry?
ほっといてよ ホッとできない
Leave me alone, I can't catch my breath.
見ないように目を逸らしたって
Even if I look away so I don't see it,
ついてくるじゃん やっぱり
you're still following me, as I thought.
転がったら起きればいいじゃん
If you fall down, you can just get back up, right?
失ったら探せばいいじゃん
If you lose it, you can just search for it, right?
いやいやいやいやいやいやいやいやいや
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no,
それでよくない？
isn't that good enough?
間違ったら直せばいいじゃん
If you make a mistake, you can just fix it, right?
やんなくなったらやめればいいじゃん
If you don't feel like doing it anymore, you can just quit, right?
いやいやいやいやいやいやいやいやいや
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no...
それって良くない？
Isn't that bad?
僕の胸も覗かないよ
You don't even look into my heart
だから僕のこと そっとして
So please just leave me alone
いやなこと全部大丈夫だと
If only I could say that all the bad things
言えたらいいのにな
are actually totally fine...
思えたらいいのにな
If only I could believe that...
違うよデタラメな大正解
No, that's a bullshit correct answer
いつも僕はそんなロールなの
I've always played that kind of role
また言いたいこと殺すから
Since I'll suppress what I want to say again,
もう忘れてくれ
just forget about me already
うわはは うざいだけのバカに はいはいはいウケる
Wahahaha! To the annoying idiots: "Yeah, yeah, so funny"
また脳の奥閉まってるね だとか
Saying things like "Your brain has shut down again"
本当は怯えている
When in reality, I'm just terrified...
吠えるだけの弱虫だったった
...a coward who does nothing but bark
痛い傷に耐えて はいはいはい
Enduring painful wounds, yeah, yeah, yeah
いつも平気なフリばっかなの
Always pretending that I'm completely fine
僕は壁を貼ったまま笑う
I smile while keeping my walls up
それ以上近づかないでどうか
Please, don't get any closer than that
ほんとバカばっか いい加減ばっか
Seriously, everyone is an idiot, so half-assed
こんなバズばっか だって待って
Nothing but trends like this, wait, wait
そんなことばっか思う僕もやっぱ
In the end, thinking about nothing but that...
どうしようもないんだ バッテン頂戴
...makes me hopeless too, so give me an X
耐え難いこととか耐えてらんないない
I can't stand things that are unbearable
死ねるって僕も口ばっかだね
Saying "I could die," I'm all talk too, aren't I?
今日も壁を貼ったまま笑う
Today, too, I smile while keeping my walls up
それ以上近づかないで
Don't get any closer than that...
怖いじゃん バカばっか
It's scary, isn't it? Idiots, all idiots
ほらバカばっか
Look, nothing but idiots...
はい、ということで重大告知ライブ始まりました！
Alright, and with that, the major announcement live has begun!
皆さん待ったよねー？
Everyone, you've been waiting, right?
秘密結社holoXの女幹部、鷹嶺ルイと申します！
I'm Takane Lui, executive officer of Secret Society holoX!
ということで、みんな見えとるぞ、コメント。
With that said, I can see everyone's comments!
お、拍手いっぱいありがとうな！拍手いっぱいありがとう！
Oh, thank you so much for all the applause! Thank you!
ということで、本日のハッシュタグはですね、こちら！こちらになりますね。
So, today's hashtag is... this one! It's right here.
ハッシュタグ #鷹嶺ルイ重大告知LIVE で
With the hashtag #TakaneLuiMajorAnnouncementLIVE,
たくさん呟いて... あ、呟きじゃないわ。
please tweet a lot... Ah, it's not "tweet" anymore.
ポストしてくれると嬉しいです！
I'd be happy if you post!
みんな今すぐポストしてください！
Everyone, please post right now!
ということで、もう一曲目、二曲目とね、Overdose、ばかいぱっかとね、
So, we've already had the first and second songs, "Overdose" and "Baka Ipakka"...
熱い曲が続いたんですけれども、
high-energy songs kept coming,
一曲目からなんと！特別ゲストが登場してくださいました！
and for the first song, we actually had a special guest join us!
ちょっとね、おしゃべりしたいと思いますので、呼びたいと思います！
I'd like to chat a bit, so I'm going to call her out!
ベイチーちゃん！
Bae-chan!
あれ？あれあれあれ？
Huh? Oh? Huh?
来たー！
She's here!
Wassup! 我々はカオスの果てのエンド、
Wassup! We are the end of chaos,
降臨のニューエイジ、一緒にクルクル回らん？汝の友、ホロENのハコス・ベールズです！
the descending new age! Want to spin around together? Your friend, Hakos Baelz of HoloEN!
ふー！
Woo!
ということで、ベイチーちゃんとはね、Overdoseを一緒に歌わせていただいたんですけれども、
So, Bae-chan and I sang "Overdose" together!
めっちゃ嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
嬉しい！私も嬉しい！ベイチーちゃんとは、
I'm happy! I'm happy too! With Bae-chan...
本当に、あの、一緒に歌いたくて。
I really wanted to sing together.
同じです。
Me too!
めっちゃ嬉しい！いや、ルイねえの曲めっちゃ好きなんで、
I'm so happy! I really love Lui-nee's songs.
ね、めっちゃかっこよくて、
They're so cool,
いや、ようやく歌えましたね。
and we finally got to sing together!
歌えました！ね、Overdoseね、絶対にベイチーちゃんに合うと思って。
We did! I thought "Overdose" would definitely suit Bae-chan.
うれしい！やっぱカオスなんでね。
I'm glad! Well, it's chaos after all.
いや、嬉しい、一緒に歌えて。
I'm so happy we could sing together.
ちょっとね、あの、最後のとこちょっとやらかした。
Actually, I kind of messed up a bit at the very end.
え、嘘？ちょっと、あの、全然分からなかったよ、多分。
Wait, really? Wait, I don't think anyone noticed, probably.
いや、多分ね、振りはね、
Well, probably, the choreography...
言っていい？これ。いいよ。振りは、元々はなかったんだよね。
Can I say it? / Sure. / Originally, there was no choreo, right?
で、なんかリハ中に「あ、ちょっと振り付けようか」みたいな話になってて、
But during rehearsal, we were like, "Oh, maybe we should add some choreo."
「ええー！やばい！」って。で、ちょっと最後のとこ忘れちゃって、すいません。
"Oh my gosh, oh no!" And then I forgot the last part, I'm sorry!
いやいやいや、全然、全然分からなかった！
No, no, no, not at all! I couldn't tell at all!
やっぱりさ、テンション上がっちゃうとね。
But you know, when your energy gets high...
わかるー！いや、でも楽しんでくれたんだよね？きっとね。
I know, right! But you had fun, right? I'm sure you did.
めっちゃ楽しい！めちゃくちゃ楽しい！
It was so much fun! Super fun!
嬉しい！私もベイチーちゃんの曲も本当に大好きで、
I'm so glad! I really love Bae-chan's songs too,
いつかベイチーちゃんの曲も挑戦したいななんて。
and I'd love to try singing one of yours someday.
ぜひぜひ！聞きたい、聞きたい！
Please do! I want to hear it!
一緒に歌ってくれますか？
Will you sing it with me?
もう、ぜひです！いや、ルイねえの『PSYCHO』聞きたいかも。
Oh, absolutely! I'd love to hear Lui-nee's "PSYCHO".
え？『PSYCHO』ね！いや、『PSYCHO』難しいけど、え、ぜひ一緒に歌いましょう！
Huh? "PSYCHO"! Well, "PSYCHO" is hard, but yes, let's sing it together!
歌いましょう！おねがいします！
Let's do it! Please!
おねがいします！
Please!
ということで、21時半からですね、ごろ...あ、21時半頃にですね、
So, around 21:30... Ah, around 9:30 PM...
重大告知を！
a major announcement...
させていただきますので、もうちょっとお待ちいただけますと幸いです！
will be made, so we'd appreciate it if you could wait just a bit longer!
Big announcement at 9:30 PM JST!
Thank you! Thank you a lot!
海外ニキもね、返事してくれるんじゃないかな？大丈夫、大丈夫かな？
I'm sure our overseas fans will reply too, right? Hopefully!
ということで、この後はですね、事前収録で来ていただいた、
So, after this, we have a pre-recorded part...
ゲストさんのパートになりますので、
from another guest...
一緒に、じゃあ、VTRのキュー振りしてもらうことできますか、ベイチーちゃん？
so Bae-chan, could you do the transition cue for the video with me?
Yes!
それでは、皆さん、この後も楽しんでいってください！
Alright, everyone, please continue to enjoy the rest of the stream!
せーの、
Ready...
VTR、どうぞ！
Here is the video!
ホロホーク / 作詞・作曲・編曲 てにをは
[Title: HoloHawk / Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: tenioha]
単純で明快で簡単じゃない
It's not simple, clear, and easy.
まだ想像と妄想と偏見で Why?
Still, with imagination, delusion, and prejudice... why?
そりゃ完全な万全な設定じゃない
Well, it's not a perfect, flawless setup.
からかってくれないか
Why don't you tease me?
外見と内面と偶像の不一致
Discrepancy between appearance, inside, and idol image.
この繊細さ敏感さ共有しよ
Let's share this sensitivity and delicacy.
ほら冷静な表情は実際ちょーハイ
Look, this cool expression is actually super high!
見つけてくれないか
Won't you find me?
はいはいお姉さん しまっちゃって行こう
Yes, yes, big sister, let's pack it up and go!
はいはい期待感 背負っちゃって行こう
Yes, yes, expectations, let's shoulder them and go!
はいはいお姉さん しまっちゃって行こう
Yes, yes, big sister, let's pack it up and go!
はいはい期待感 背負っちゃって行こう
Yes, yes, expectations, let's shoulder them and go!
ホロホーク ホロホーク だけど高嶺の花
HoloHawk, HoloHawk, but like a flower on a high peak...
みたいに扱っちゃ嫌
please don't treat me like that.
あのね 誰も彼もワシと勘違い
You see, everyone confuses me with an eagle.
驚きのアイ
An eye of surprise!
ホロホーク ホロホーク だけどPONコツみがちょい
HoloHawk, HoloHawk, but with a bit of clumsiness...
あるだけで親近感
just having that makes you feel close.
その際 その差異 そのサイ 受け止めてよね
At that moment, that difference, accept it, okay?
鷹嶺の未来 乾杯
A toast to the future of Takane!
しっかりウォッチ
Watch closely.
曖昧 You Know
Vague, you know.
狩りとか苦手
I'm not good at hunting.
猛禽ルイ姉
Bird of prey, Sister Lui.
一見クールね
Cool at first glance, right?
意外とギャップ系
Surprisingly full of gap moe.
イメージ大変身
A total image makeover.
OK?
大衆の歓声って内臓じゃない？
Isn't the crowd's cheer like our internal organs?
ありゃ心配ね 相談ね 散々ね もう
That's worrying, a consultation, terrible, really!
ただ正論や暴論の配信じゃない
It's not just a stream of sound arguments or extreme views.
個人的見解対正解
Personal opinion vs. correct answer.
ホロホーク ホロホーク だけど捕食しないさ
HoloHawk, HoloHawk, but I won't prey on you.
だから怖がっちゃ嫌
So please don't be scared.
ほらね 爪も羽もお洒落に研いで
See, claws and feathers are stylishly groomed,
隠しちゃいない
and I'm not hiding them.
ホロホーク ホロホーク だけど観察眼がちょい
HoloHawk, HoloHawk, but with a bit of observation skill...
あるだけで緊張感
just having that brings a sense of tension.
その際 その差異 そのサイ その差 受け止めてよね
At that moment, that difference, accept it, okay?
鷹まる時代 乾杯
A toast to the rising era!
はいはいお姉さん しまっちゃって行こう
Yes, yes, big sister, let's pack it up and go!
はいはい期待感 背負っちゃって行こう
Yes, yes, expectations, let's shoulder them and go!
はいはいお姉さん しまっちゃって行こう
Yes, yes, big sister, let's pack it up and go!
はいはい期待感 背負っちゃって行こう
Yes, yes, expectations, let's shoulder them and go!
ホロホーク ホロホーク だけど高嶺の花
HoloHawk, HoloHawk, but like a flower on a high peak...
みたいに扱っちゃ嫌
please don't treat me like that.
あのね 誰も彼もワシと勘違い
You see, everyone confuses me with an eagle.
驚きのアイ
An eye of surprise!
ホロホーク ホロホーク だけどPONコツみがちょい
HoloHawk, HoloHawk, but with a bit of clumsiness...
あるだけで親近感
just having that makes you feel close.
その際 その差異 そのサイ その差
At that moment, that difference, that gap...
受け止めてよね
accept it, okay?
鷹嶺の未来 乾杯
A toast to the future of Takane!
愛じゃん 鷹まる時代 乾杯
It's love! A toast to the rising era!
END
魔眼ウインク / 作詞・作曲・編曲 てにをは
[Title: Magan Wink / Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: tenioha]
Sorry
to be late
Do you remember me?
魅せる目と目が合ったらきっと落下下
When our captivating eyes meet, we'll surely fall further down.
足んない爪はもう真っ赤っ赤
Our lacking claws are already bright red.
それは Wink off Wink off 逃げてもずっと落下下
That is a Wink off, Wink off, even if you run you'll keep falling down.
I'm Crazyな台風の目
I'm the crazy eye of the storm.
Wink
Show down お目が高い 目に入れたって痛くないくらい
Showdown, you have great taste, so dear to me.
クチバシに Sweet Vengeance
Sweet vengeance on my beak.
憎しみならとっくに捨てた
If it's hatred, I threw it away long ago.
怖がってんの？ あっそ
Are you scared? Oh really?
Don't let me down Eyes on me now
まだまだ Eyes on me now
Still not enough, eyes on me now.
安全じゃないから？ 健全じゃないから？
Is it because it's not safe? Is it because it's not wholesome?
それがなんだ
So what of it?
Franticだね 目には目を
It's frantic, isn't it? An eye for an eye...
La la la la la
Wink! Say la la la 赤裸々 Gimme
Wink! Say la la la, bare it all, gimme.
Wink! Say liar liar liar 真っ赤っ赤っ赤
Wink! Say liar liar liar, bright red.
Oh, EYE, EYE, EYE want you で バイバイスペル
Oh, eye, eye, I want you, so bye-bye spell.
バイバイ 怨嗟
Bye-bye, resentment.
目に物見せる My EYE EYE
I'll show you what's what, My EYE EYE.
いいよ 目を瞑るの半分ね
Fine, closing only half your eyes, right?
魔眼ウィンク
Evil Eye Wink.
有能が絢爛降臨
The talented descend in splendor.
魔眼ウィンク
Evil Eye Wink.
My god, My god
ほらご覧 瞬く間に
Look, in the blink of an eye,
EYE'll kill you... Wink
後ろ指指したいなら お好きにどうぞ
If you want to point fingers behind our backs, go ahead.
当方 当世 振り返らぬ所存の金輪際
We have absolutely no intention of ever looking back at this world.
お待たせ Suck out, Suck out
Thanks for waiting, Suck out, Suck out.
おさらば 恨み Cut, Cut
Farewell, resentment, Cut, Cut.
無礼講な祭り目
An informal celebratory feast for the eyes.
I'm coming back, coming back, coming back
夢じゃない 渦中になる
It's no dream, you're in the center of it.
そうさ 良好じゃないだろう 最良じゃないだろう
That's right, it's not just good, it's not the best.
それがどうしたんだ Franticだね
But what of it? It's frantic, isn't it?
目には目を 歯には羽を
An eye for an eye, a feather for a tooth.
C'est la vie
類は何を呼ぶ？
What does kind attract?
C'est la vie 羽ばたき 走るウィンク 目が離せない
C'est la vie, fluttering wings, a running wink, you can't take your eyes off us.
完璧なウィンク
The perfect wink.
Say La La La Lovin' 赤裸々 Gimme
Say La La La Lovin' nakedly, Gimme.
And Wink Say La La La Liar 真っ赤っかだ
And Wink, Say La La La Liar, it's bright red.
Oh EYE EYE EYE EYE want you で
Oh, EYE EYE EYE, with "I want you".
バイバイ 怨嗟
Bye-bye, resentment.
目に物見せる My EYE EYE
I'll show you what's what, My EYE EYE.
もう 目が離せない EYE EYE 魔眼ウィンク
I can't take my eyes off you anymore, EYE EYE, Evil Eye Wink.
魔眼ウィンク
Evil Eye Wink.
My god, My god
ほらご覧 瞬く間に
Look, in the blink of an eye,
EYE EYE EYE EYE'll kill you
Wink off
Wink
弾けない
I can't back down...
なんてありえない
That's impossible.
後に引けない
No backing out now.
無闇にひけらかさない fly...
I won't show off recklessly, fly...
いつも突然のハラハラ 火花散らせば命からがら
Always a sudden thrill, when sparks fly it's a narrow escape.
待ったなし 媚びずダンシング
No waiting around, dancing without playing favorites.
巧みなステップで躱しちゃうぜ
We'll dodge it with our skillful steps.
サラリーな社会が眠る頃に
When the salaried society is fast asleep.
パラリラ輩跋っこするコロニー
In a colony where ruffians run wild.
持ちつ持たれつ表裏一体をくぐり抜けて
Navigating the give-and-take, two sides of the same coin.
平日は shoo be doo be do
Weekdays are shoo be doo be do.
週末も shoo be doo be do
Weekends too are shoo be doo be do.
時にきつくハードに 時に平和なバードみ
Sometimes strict and hard, sometimes peaceful bird-style.
今宵 ひみつのおしごと
Tonight is a secret job.
綺羅煌々 狙って bang-ba-bang
Shining brilliantly, aiming bang-ba-bang.
外さない クリア
Never missing, clear.
いざ堂々 目立って run and gun
Boldly and proudly, standing out, run and gun.
未だに他に類を見ない
Still unparalleled elsewhere.
意気揚々 迫って bang-ba-bang
Triumphant, closing in bang-ba-bang.
悟られず カバー
Undetected, cover.
here we go yo 気取ってさぁ出番
Here we go yo, striking a pose, it's our turn.
跡を濁さず take off
Leaving no trace behind, take off.
けして逃がさない
Never letting them escape.
剥いた牙を抜くまで
Until we draw their bared fangs.
けして汚さない
Never letting it be stained.
守る無二の看板
Protecting our one-and-only reputation.
気取られない根回し oh yeah
Unnoticed behind-the-scenes groundwork, oh yeah.
お見舞いする後の祭り oh yeah
Too late to regret once we're done, oh yeah.
響くヒールの音がお仕置きの合図
The echoing sound of heels is the signal for punishment.
誰も彼も check out my ホークアイ
Everyone, check out my hawk-eye.
年始から shoo be doo be do
From the start of the year, shoo be doo be do.
年末も shoo be doo be do
To the end of the year, shoo be doo be do.
お任せあれハンドリング 表に出せない後処理 もとい ひみつのおしごと
Leave the handling to us, dealing with the aftermath behind closed doors... I mean, a secret job.
綺羅煌々 狙って bang-ba-bang
Shining brilliantly, aiming bang-ba-bang.
外さない クリア
Never missing, clear.
いざ堂々 目立って run and gun
Boldly and proudly, standing out, run and gun.
しばしば類は友を呼ぶ
Often, birds of a feather flock together.
意気揚々 迫って bang-ba-bang
Triumphant, closing in bang-ba-bang.
悟られず カバー
Undetected, cover.
here we go yo 気取ってさぁ出番
Here we go yo, striking a pose, it's our turn.
爪を剥き出し beat you
Baring our claws to beat you.
たかが企業もどきと侮るのなら
If you look down on us as just some mock corporation.
タガが外れて容赦できなくなって やばっ！炸裂！
We'll lose our minds and show no mercy, oh no! Explosion!
本音かまし 弱音なんてすぐねんね
Letting out our true feelings, putting any weakness right to sleep.
混じり気ないハートビート 揺らすこの世界
A pure heartbeat shaking this world.
最果てまで届くよう鳴らした鐘
Ringing the bell so it reaches the ends of the earth.
裏の裏までいただいちゃおう
Let's take it all, down to the very core of their secrets.
綺羅煌々 狙って bang-ba-bang
Shining brilliantly, aiming bang-ba-bang.
外さない クリア
Never missing, clear.
いざ堂々 目立って run and gun
Boldly and proudly, standing out, run and gun.
未だに他に類を見ない
Still unparalleled elsewhere.
意気揚々 迫って bang-ba-bang
Triumphant, closing in bang-ba-bang.
悟られず カバー
Undetected, cover.
here we go yo 気取ってさぁ出番
Here we go yo, striking a pose, it's our turn.
跡を濁さず take off
Leaving no trace behind, take off.
今日もひみつの take off
Today too, a secret take off.
Shoo be do to be do do
今日もひみつの Take off
Another secret takeoff today
立派なこの羽に
On these fine wings,
泥をつけて這っていた
I was crawling through the mud,
兼ね備えた爪立てて
with my well-equipped claws dug in.
信じられるものは自分だけだと
Believing that the only one I can trust is myself,
思い込んで進み続けた
I kept pushing forward.
「あのコみたいにすれば？」
"Why don't you do it like that girl?"
「君じゃそれは無理だ」
"It's impossible for you."
言わせておけばいいさ
Let them say what they want.
たった独り 逆境の先
All alone, beyond adversity,
あいつらから奪う歓声
I will steal their cheers.
私の邪魔させやしない
I won't let them stand in my way!
like a 高嶺 見据えた高み
Like a lofty peak, gazing at the heights,
穴ぐらから空へ
from the cave to the sky,
飛んでいく私を見ないなんて
how could you not watch me fly away?
bad boy
「あのコはもう終わりだ」
"That girl is done."
「これ以上はないね」
"She won't get any further."
言わせておけばいいさ
Let them say what they want.
いつの日か...
Someday...
寝ても覚めても
whether asleep or awake,
夢見てた大歓声
I've dreamed of the great cheers.
私はここで死にたくない！
I don't want to die here!
一生の旅 逆境の先
A lifelong journey, beyond adversity,
あいつらから奪う歓声
I will steal their cheers.
私の邪魔させやしない
I won't let them stand in my way!
like a 高嶺 見据えた高み
Like a lofty peak, gazing at the heights,
穴ぐらから空へ
from the cave to the sky,
飛んでいく私を見ないなんて
how could you not watch me fly away?
bad boy
誰かに言われなくたって
Even if nobody says so,
私の方がもっと嫌いだ
I hate myself even more.
うるさいな
Shut up.
想像が視界を塞いで
Imagination blocks my vision,
惨めな理由を書き連ねる
writing down miserable excuses,
教室にずっと居残り
left behind in the classroom forever.
窓の向こうに黒い影があって
A black shadow stands outside the window,
何も言わずにこっちを見ていた
staring at me without a word.
私は貴方に救われたくて泣くんじゃない
I don't cry because I want you to save me.
産声は止められないもの
The first cry cannot be stopped.
何千回ともう一度死に損なおう
Let's fail to die once again, thousands of times,
希望と絶望の夜中を纏って
cloaked in the midnight of hope and despair.
醜い光を許したのは
The one who forgave the ugly light
他ならない私だった
was none other than myself.
息をして
Take a breath...
目を開けて
...and open your eyes.
これが最後かどうか
Whether this is the end or not,
知る術はないよ 知りたくもないよ
I have no way of knowing, nor do I want to know.
優しいな
How kind...
昏々と闇は寄り添って
darkness gently nestles in.
どうせ面白くもないよと
"Anyway, it's not even interesting..."
窓を挟んで微かに聞こえた
I faintly heard it through the window...
それは祈るような啜り泣きだった
...it was a prayer-like sobbing.
私は貴方を救える言葉を知らないけど
I don't know the words to save you, but...
寂しいねって声をかけた
...I called out, "It's lonely, isn't it?"
何千回ともう一度死に損なおう
Let's fail to die once again, thousands of times,
希望と絶望の夜中を纏って
wearing the night of hope and despair.
何千回ともう一度生きる貴方へ
To you who will live once again, thousands of times...
私も続くよ 窓の向こう側で
...I will follow you on the other side of the window.
醜い光を愛せたとき
When we could love the ugly light...
終わらせなかった産声を
...the first cry that we didn't let end...
歌にしよう
...let's turn it into a song.
Let's turn it into a song.
歌にしよう
特報
[Special Announcement]
戦う理由は、一つじゃない
[There is more than one reason to fight]
Lapis Lazuli
[Lapis Lazuli - Takane Lui 2nd Album]
はい、ということで、今、特報を見ていただきましたが、
Yes! So you've just watched the special announcement,
なんと、鷹嶺ルイ、12月3日に
and surprisingly, Takane Lui, on December 3rd...
自身のセカンドアルバム『Lapis Lazuli』を
...will be releasing her second album, "Lapis Lazuli"!
発売することが決定しました！
It has been officially decided!
ふー！いぇーい！
Woo! Yay!
ということで
And so,
なんとですね、今回は鷹嶺史上初の
surprisingly, for the first time in Takane's history,
全国、全国のショップで買える全国流通盤ということで
this will be a nationwide distribution, available at shops all over Japan!
えー、また一つ夢が叶っちゃいました
Ah, another dream of mine has come true,
みんなのおかげです、ありがとう！
all thanks to everyone. Thank you!
えー、ファーストに続きまして、リバティに続きまして、セカンドなんですけども
Following my first album, then Liberty, this is my second,
今回は『Lapis Lazuli』というね、タイトルを付けさせていただきました+
but this time, I've titled it "Lapis Lazuli."
この『Lapis Lazuli』というのはですね
This "Lapis Lazuli" is...
いつも、あの、アルバムには『L』の文字がついてるんですけれども
Well, my albums always have the letter "L" in their title,
えー、今回も『L』の文字から始まる『Lapis Lazuli』という言葉で
so this time too, I chose "Lapis Lazuli" starting with "L."
えー、こちらですね、あの、意味がですね
This word actually has meanings,
えー、成功に導く、だったりとか
such as "leading to success,"
あとは、結構、あの、勝利へと、勝利を掴み取る、みたいな
and also grasping victory, or moving towards victory,
意味合いが込められておりまして
those kinds of meanings are infused into it.
なんと、こちらアルバムはですね、VS、戦いをテーマにした曲になっております
Remarkably, this album contains songs themed around "VS" and conflict,
あ、曲ばかりになっておりますので
or rather, it's packed with songs like that.
そういった意味合いも込めて、Lapis Lazuliという名前を付けさせていただきました
So with that meaning, I named it "Lapis Lazuli."
さらに、なんとですね、秋葉原ゲーマーズ本店さんでも
Furthermore, remarkably, at the Akihabara Gamers Main Store,
リリース記念ライブをやらせていただくことになりました！いぇーい！
we will be holding a release commemoration live! Yay!
なんと、ミニライブも開催ということで
Yes, a mini-live is also scheduled to be held!
えー、本日ですね、12時半から予約開始となっているので、もう
Pre-orders started today at 12:30 PM, so
すでに予約ができる状態になっております
they are already available for pre-order now!
えー、みなさんも見えますかね？
Can everyone see it?
えー、画面の左下
In the bottom left of the screen...
左下にボタンありますか？
Is there a button in the bottom left?
みんなある？ボタン
Does everyone see it? The button.
あるかしら
I wonder if you do.
そこからですね、購入ボタンがありますので、そこから予約ができるようになりましたので
There is a purchase button there, and you can pre-order from there,
ぜひぜひ、こちらから予約してみてください
so please go ahead and pre-order from there!
ということで、アルバムの詳細をね、パッとお話しさせていただこうかなと思うんですけども
So, I'd like to quickly talk about the album details,
おめでとう、ありがとう、みんな
but first, thank you everyone for the congratulations!
えー、収録楽曲についてはこちらになります。とぅるん！
Here are the tracks included in the album. Ta-da!
はい、えー、先行リリースしておりますジグザグをはじめ
Yes! Starting with "ZIG-ZAG", which has been pre-released,
先ほども言いました、VS、戦いをテーマにした
and as I mentioned, it features 10 tracks in total
全10曲が収録されています
themed around "VS" and conflict.
えー、6曲目にはですね、みなさん、お分かりですか？
For the 6th track, as you might have noticed...
フィーチャリング・ラプラス・ダークネスということで
...it features La+ Darknesss!
と、一緒に歌った曲も収録されております。そしてですね...
The song we sang together is also included. Also...
色々、な、言いたいことはあるんですけど
There are many things I want to say,
1つ1つ言いたいんですけれど、ちょっとお時間がないので
I'd love to go over them one by one, but since we are short on time...
10曲目の「抗う君への鎮魂歌」という曲はですね
the 10th track, "Requiem for You Who Resist"...
とあるアニメのイメージソングになっておりますので
is the image song for a certain anime.
これから色々情報が出てくると思いますので
As more information will be coming out,
楽しみに待っていただければなと思います。
please look forward to it!
そして！
And...
完全生産限定盤はこんな感じになっております！どうぞ！
the Complete Limited Edition looks like this! Take a look!
お、どうぞ、あ、こっちだ。どうぞ、あ、こっちだ。
Oh, here it is... Ah, this way. Here it is... Ah, this way.
スライドボックス式でですね
It's a slide box design.
あの、2人の鷹嶺ルイを、あの、離したりくっつけたりできる
You can slide the two Takane Luis together or apart.
オシャレでしょ？しかも「Liberty」と
Isn't it stylish? Plus, just like with "Liberty"...
同じSOLANIさんがイラストを担当してくださいました！
SOLANI-san did the illustration for this one too!
めちゃくちゃかっこよくないですか？ぜひぜひね
Isn't it super cool? Please do try...
あの、戦わせたり離したりして、遊んでみてください。
making them fight or separating them, and have fun!
他にも、このようなグッズもございます。
We have other items like this as well.
完全生産限定盤にはですね
The Complete Limited Edition...
えー、今までのリリースした楽曲のジャケットを
features an illustration book containing the jacket art...
えー、入れ込んだ「ジャケットイラストブック」。これね、私が欲しいって言ったんですよ。
of previously released songs. I actually requested this myself!
えー、そしたらね、無理やり欲しいって言ったんですけど
I kind of forced them by insisting I wanted it...
なんと実現をしてくださいまして、今までの
but they actually made it a reality!
リリースした楽曲のジャケットが、1つの本になって見れる
So now you can see all the past song jackets in one book.
やつになっております。
That's how it turned out.
いや、みんな欲しかったっしょ？
I mean, you all wanted this too, right?
いや、私が欲しいものはきっとみんなが欲しいと思いまして
I figured that if I want it, everyone else would want it too!
えー、こちらちょっと無理やりに作っていただきました。
So, I kind of forced them to make this.
ご協力してくださった関係者の皆さん、ありがとうございます。
Thank you to all the staff who co-operated!
そしてですね、オリジナル缶バッジも2種類付いて、そしてそして
Also, it comes with two original tin badges, and...
今回もですね、完全生産限定盤にだけになるんですけれども
this applies only to the Complete Limited Edition, but...
直筆サイン入りジャケットカードを、購入者全員
there will be a hand-signed jacket card for everyone...
皆さんに、直筆サインさせていただきますので
who purchases it! I will sign each one myself,
ぜひぜひ完全生産限定盤、色んな特典がありますので、買って
so please get the Complete Limited Edition to enjoy all the bonuses.
いただけますと幸いでございます。
I would really appreciate it!
さらに、通常盤はこちら！
Next, here is the Standard Edition!
はい。
Yes!
通常盤にはですね、ランダムアナザージャケット、1枚入り
The Standard Edition includes one random alternate jacket...
全5種類ある中の、1枚が入っております。
out of 5 different types.
そして、こちらもですね、数量限定ランダムで
And, also in limited quantities, at random...
鷹嶺ルイの直筆サイン、そして
there will be some with my hand-signed signature...
コメントも付いてきます！直筆コメントも付いてきます！
and a handwritten comment! Yes, a comment too!
ちょっとこちらはランダムになっちゃうんですけれども
This bonus will be random, but...
ぜひぜひ、皆さんに当たりますように！
I hope you all get one!
通常盤もぜひ買ってみてください。
Please consider getting the Standard Edition as well.
そしてそして、各ショップの法人特典はこちらになります！ドジャン！
And here are the store-specific bonuses! Ta-da!
Amazon様、マウスパッドだったり、色々なね
Amazon has mouse pads, and there are various other...
お店で、色んな特典が付いておりますので
bonuses available at different retailers.
皆さん欲しいものがあれば、そちらで予約してくださると
If there's something you like, I'd be happy if you reserve there.
嬉しいでございます。また詳細などは
Also, details about this...
ポストしますので、そちらで詳しく見ていってください。
will be posted, so please check there for more information.
はい！
Okay!
さらに、こちら！
Next, look at this!
先ほどもお伝えしました、秋葉原ゲーマーズ本店さんにて
As I mentioned earlier, at Akihabara Gamers Main Store...
12月7日に、リリース記念ミニライブの開催が決定しました！
a release commemorative mini-live will be held on December 7th!
ゲーマーズさんで
For those who purchase...
アルバムを購入した人の中から抽選で
the album at Gamers, you'll be entered into a lottery
ミニライブにご招待をさせていただきます！
to be invited to the mini-live!
ぜひゲーマーズさんでもアルバムを買ってくださると嬉しいでございます！
I'd be glad if you buy the album at Gamers too!
ということで、今回ですね
So this time...
あの、皆さんの左下にあるボタンではですね、完全生産限定盤
the button on the bottom left of your screen will take you...
と通常盤のところに、ECサイトに飛ぶのかな？
to the online store for the Complete Limited and Standard Editions, I think?
多分オフィシャルサイトに飛びますので
It probably links to the official site,
皆さん、そちらで完全生産限定盤だったりとかが欲しいよっていう方はそちらで
so if you want the Complete Limited Edition, you can...
予約をしていただきまして、ちょっと他の
pre-order it there. For those who want to...
ショップさんで予約をしたいよという方はね、詳細
pre-order from other stores, the details...
後ほど、あの、X、そして
will be available later on X and...
概要欄にも貼らせていただきますので、そちらでチェックをしていただけると嬉しいでございます。
in the description section. I'd appreciate it if you could check there.
いや、ラピスラズリ。しかもですね、ちょっとラピスラズリって
Lapis Lazuli... Also, you know, for Lapis Lazuli...
あの、誕生月、誕生石が、9月と12月ということで
the birthstone months are September and December.
なんと、9月に私重大発表をして
And surprisingly, I made this major announcement in September...
12月に発売っていうね。
and the album will be released in December!
あ、これたままななんですけど、たまたまって言わない方がいいよね。これね、あの
Ah, this was actually coincidental, but maybe I shouldn't say that. Actually, this was...
うん、あの、仕掛けなんですね、これ。
planned all along!
仕掛けさせていただきました。
I planned it that way!
偶然、偶然じゃなくて、ちゃんと、ちゃんと考え、ちゃんと、ちゃんと考えました。
It's not a coincidence, I really thought it through!
なので、私の夢であり...
Therefore, as it was my dream...
ました。全国流通版のセカンドアルバムもぜひぜひ皆さん、
So, I would be very happy if everyone would purchase
ご購入いただけますと幸いです。よろしくお願いします。
the nationwide release of my second album. Thank you so much!
それでは、まだまだ歌っていきたいと思います。
Now, I'm going to keep singing!
この後もまだまだ告知がございますので、お楽しみに。
There are still more announcements to come, so please look forward to it.
ちょっと水を飲んでもいいですか？水を飲んでもいいですね。
Can I drink some water? It's fine to drink water, right?
水を飲みます。ちょっと待ってください。
I'll drink some water. Please wait a bit.
飲みました。
I'm done drinking!
ということで、まだお一人、えー、ゲストが出てない方がいらっしゃいますね。
So, there is still one... guest who hasn't appeared yet.
その方はいつ出るんでしょうか？お見逃しなく。
I wonder when they will show up? Don't miss it!
ということで続いての曲、行きましょうか。皆さん準備は大丈夫ですか？
With that, let's move on to the next song. Is everyone ready?
準備は大丈夫ですね。それでは。
Yes, you're ready! Here we go.
はい、それでは聴いてください。「ZIG-ZAG」
Alright, please listen. "ZIG-ZAG".
1, 2, 3, 4!
ということで、もう一人の特別ゲストを呼びたいと思います！
So, I'd like to call out our other special guest!
星街すいせい！盛り上がっていきましょう！
Hoshimachi Suisei! Let's pump things up!
「幸せ？」って囁いた吐息はラッタラッタラ
The sigh that whispered "Are you happy?" went rat-ta-rat-ta
媚びついて離れはしないわラッタラッタラ
Clinging to me and never letting go, rat-ta-rat-ta
無味無臭の生活が思い出せないや
I can't even remember my tasteless, odorless life anymore
忘れたいから歌った、馬鬼だラッタラッタラ
I sang because I wanted to forget. How foolish, rat-ta-rat-ta
恨むことも　憎むことも
Both holding grudges and harboring hatred
賢くはない故にできなかった
I couldn't do, because I wasn't smart enough
これが君の結末ならば
If this is your ending,
笑ってしまいたいほど　嘘嘘嘘
it makes me want to just laugh it off. Lies, lies, lies!
「嘘つき」
Liar.
痛い痛い痛い痛いな　奇跡とかちょっと望んじゃって
It hurts, it hurts, it hurts, it hurts... I hoped for a miracle
もう嫌いやいやいやいや　性質が悪いわ
No, I hate, hate, hate, hate it. What a nasty personality
狙い狙い狙い狙いな　おかしなとこ全部えぐり取って
Aim, aim, aim, aim... gouge out all the weird parts
薄情で結構、好きに呼んでいいよ
Coldhearted is fine, call me whatever you want
トラウマにバイバイしたいのです　ですですですです
I want to say bye-bye to my trauma. I do, I do, I do, I do!
私、甘え上手になれなかった
I couldn't become good at playing pampered
可愛げとかが足りなかった　後悔がうるさい、オルタ
I lacked cuteness. Regret is so loud, my alter ego
「過去は過去だ」と割り切っちゃえば　きっと良いことあるさ
If I just tell myself "the past is the past", surely good things will happen,
とかそれくらい　百も承知だラッタラッタラ
or something like that, I already know that perfectly well, rat-ta-rat-ta
願うことも　祈ることも
Both wishing and praying
許されないから黒く染めた
Are not allowed, so I dyed them black
元の色も　思い出せない
I can't even remember the original color
絡まった　不明の糸、糸、糸、糸
Tangled up in an unknown thread, thread, thread, thread
痛い痛い痛い痛いな　悲劇のヒロイン気取っちゃって
It hurts, it hurts, it hurts, it hurts... pretending to be a tragic heroine
もう嫌いやいやいやいや　諦めちゃえば
No, I hate, hate, hate, hate it. If I just give up,
新生児を　事故みたいに願っちゃって
But I want to meet you, so badly... my thought circuits are bugged
明日またきっと壊すけどいいの？
I'll surely break it again tomorrow, but is that okay?
トラウマさえ愛おしいのです　ですですですです
Even the trauma is precious to me. It is, it is, it is, it is!
夢の中で君と　手を繋いでいるの
In my dreams, I'm holding hands with you
何も知らないあの頃の二人のままで
Just like the two of us back then, who knew nothing at all
でも解っているよ　すぐに醒めてしまうと
But I know that I'll wake up from it soon
それならばいっそ
If so, then I'd rather...
君の手でそっと
...with your hands, gently...
とどめ刺して　ほら、今、今、今
...finish me off. Look, now, now, now!
痛い痛い痛い痛いな　奇跡とかちょっと望んじゃって
It hurts, it hurts, it hurts, it hurts... I hoped for a miracle
もう嫌いやいやいやいや　性質が悪いわ
No, I hate, hate, hate, hate it. What a nasty personality
狙い狙い狙い狙いな　おかしなとこ全部えぐり取って
Aim, aim, aim, aim... gouge out all the weird parts
薄情で結構、好きに呼んでいいよ
Coldhearted is fine, call me whatever you want
トラウマにバイバイしたいのです　ですですですです　ですですですです
I want to say bye-bye to my trauma. I do, I do, I do, I do!
すいちゃん来てくれてありがとう！
Suisei-chan, thank you for coming!
いえーい！ルイちゃん、超楽しかったぜ！
Yay! Lui-chan, that was super fun!
いやー、嬉しいぜ！
Aw, I'm so glad!
ジグザグ、ジグザグ！
Zig-zag, zig-zag!
ジグザグ、ジグザグ、ジグザグ！
Zig-zag, zig-zag, zig-zag!
うわー！
Wow!
ということで皆さん、すいちゃんが来てくれました！
So, everyone, Suisei-chan came to join us!
はーい、来ましたよー！
Yes, I'm here!
彗星の如く現れたスターの原石、バーチャルアイドルの星街すいせいです！すいちゃんはー？
A diamond in the rough, appearing like a comet! I'm virtual idol Hoshimachi Suisei! Suisei-chan is...
今日も可愛い！
...cute as always today!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
ということで！
And so,
ルイ、セカンドアルバム発売決定おめでとう！
Lui, congratulations on your second album release!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
いや いっぱい あの いっぱい いっぱい相談しました
No, I consulted with her a lot, I mean, a lot.
いっぱい いっぱい 確かに 何回聞いたかも。なんか曲 結構知ってるかも
A lot, indeed. I even lost count of how many times I listened to it. I think I know the song pretty well.
そう、いっぱい いっぱい相談しました、すいちゃんに
Yeah. I consulted with Sui-chan so, so much.
このジグザグもね、実は、ちょっとリリース前から聞いてて
I actually listened to "Zig-Zag" before its release.
はい
Yes.
今日、そう。今日はですね、ジグザグをすいちゃんと歌いたかった理由はですね
Today, yes. The reason why I wanted to sing "Zig-Zag" with Sui-chan today is...
まあ本当にあの、歌、あの、いっぱいいっぱい相談をしたっていうのと
Well, truly, because we talked and consulted so much about it,
あと曲がね、あの、タイトルを一緒に考えてくれたんですよね、ジグザグという
and also because we thought of the title "Zig-Zag" together.
そうなんですよ！一番最初タイトル本当は違ってたんだよね
That's right! The title was actually different at first.
そう、そうなんです
Yes, that's true.
そこから、どうかなって言って。「えっ、ジグザグってトラウマって意味あるらしいよ」みたいな
From there, we wondered, and you were like, "Wait, I heard 'Zig-Zag' can mean trauma."
って、なって。一緒にね。「え、ジグザグ良くない？」みたいな
And we were like, "Wait, isn't 'Zig-Zag' perfect?"
「そうじゃない？」みたいな。「間にはいふんとか入れようぜ」って
We were like, "Right?" and "Let's put a hyphen in between!"
「え、おしゃれじゃない？」みたいな
And "Wait, isn't that stylish?!"
ね。たくさんたくさん相談をしまして
Yes. We consulted each other so, so much.
で、ジグザグ、すいちゃんに合いそうだな、みたいな
I thought "Zig-Zag" would really suit Sui-chan.
え、でもこれね、歌っててね、楽しいね
But honestly, singing this is so much fun!
楽しい
It's fun!
楽しいでしょ？ / いや、これ楽しいですよ、すごい
Right? / Yeah, this is incredibly fun!
楽しいんですよ、ぜひ。しかも、ルイとね、やっぱ、その、声質というか、このなんだろう、低音歌う組というか
It is! Also, singing with Lui, since we both have similar vocal ranges... like, the low-pitch duo...
はいはい
Right, right.
として、なんか合ってるなっていうのもすごい思ったし、歌ってて楽しかったです
I really felt our voices blended well, so I had a lot of fun singing it.
いや、もう、ジグザグ歌うんだったら、すいちゃんと歌いたいって言って、もう
I was like, "If I'm singing 'Zig-Zag', I absolutely want to sing it with Sui-chan!"
絶対すいちゃんと歌う！って言って
I said, "I must sing it with Sui-chan!"
で、あの、呼んだら快諾をしてくださいました。本当にありがとうございました、お忙しい中で
And when I invited her, she happily accepted. Thank you so much, especially when you're so busy.
いえいえ。そんなもう、生出演なんかいつでも呼んでください。そんなのね
No, not at all! Feel free to invite me for live guest appearances anytime!
ありがとうございます。 / もうコメントの皆さんもね
Thank you so much. / And to everyone in the chat, too.
はい、どうもどうも。「あ、いい、かっこいいかっこいい。合ってる合ってる。わかるわかる」って、ほらね、言ってるよね
Yes, hello, hello! See, they're saying, "Oh, nice, so cool! They match well! I get it!"
いや、本当に一緒に歌えて、本当に緊張したんだけど、一緒に歌えて良かったです。しかも2回目なんですよ、一緒に2人で歌ったの
Yeah, I was really nervous, but I'm so glad we sang together. Plus, this is actually the second time we've sung as a duo!
そうなんですよね
That's true!
そうなんです。前は、Mカードのファーストでね
Yes. Last time was during the first M-Card.
「バグ」
"Bug."
そう、「バグ」で
Yes, with "Bug."
今度は「ジグザグ」
And this time, "Zig-Zag."
「ジグザグ」。次は、何になるんでしょうか。 / 次は、何グですか？
"Zig-Zag." I wonder what's next. / What "-g" will it be next?
何グになるんでしょうか。どうぞね、今後も楽しみにして頂けたらな、と思うんですけども
I wonder what "-g" it will be. I hope you'll look forward to it in the future.
なんと、まだ告知があるんです
But wait, we still have another announcement!
え、そんなまさか！
No way!
はい、なので
Yes, so...
え？ どんなやつ？
Eh? What kind of announcement?
え、ちょっと、この、このアルバムに絡めたやつですよ
Well, it's something related to this album.
えー、何何？ 気になる気になる
Eh, what is it? I'm so curious.
気になる？じゃあ一緒に見ようか
Curious? Let's watch it together then.
え、見るんだ。一緒に見よう
Oh, we're watching it? Let's watch it.
ということで、こちらをご覧ください。どうぞ
Without further ado, please take a look.
おやはてさて 存じ上げないわ
Oh, well, well, I don't know you.
フーアーユー？
Who are you?
どっちがワタシ
Which one is me?
face to face コンニチハ
Face to face, hello.
ユーはミー？
Are you me?
もーなんてったって
No matter what,
up side down for ジブン ジブン
upside down for myself, myself.
look alike
ライクライク
Like, like.
ライクライクミー
Like, like me.
どーなって
What's going to happen?
てかオマエ
But wait, you...
てかオマエは
But wait, who are you?!
だれ！？
Who?!
昨日のジブンは
Yesterday's self,
ジブンの手で
with my own hands,
片付けましょう
let's clean up.
てかフーアーユー？
I mean, who are you?
だれ！？
Who?!
[このあとOriginal Anime MV公開!]
[Original Anime MV releasing after this!]
なんと、セカンドアルバムより、『だれ！？』が本日24時に先行デジタルリリースがされます！
Wow! From the second album, "dare !?" will have an advance digital release tonight at 24:00!
イェーイ！ / だれだれだれ？
Yay! / Who, who, who is it?
これ誰？え、こっちのルイはわかるけど、こっちのルイは誰？
Who is this? I recognize this Lui, but who is the other Lui?
誰なんだろう？ / 誰なんだろう？ / え、気になるよね。 / 気になるね
Who indeed? / Who indeed? / Makes you curious, right? / It does.
実はこの曲作った人も気にならない？ / え、気になる！
Actually, aren't you curious about who made this song too? / I am!
なんと、マガンウィングを作ってくれた、てにをはさんが今回も作成してくれたよ！
Guess what? Teniwoha-san, who made "Magan Wing", wrote this one too!
あ、てにをは節、確かに感じる！ / 感じるよね！めっちゃ感じる
Ah, I can definitely feel the Teniwoha vibe! / Right? It's totally there.
そしてこの配信終了後には、MVが公開されます！
And right after this stream ends, the MV will be released!
おー！MV、さっき流れてたやつですか？ / そうなんですよ。なんと、あの、鷹嶺ルイ史上
Oh! The MV we just saw a preview of? / That's right. Believe it or not, in Takane Lui's history...
今回、鷹嶺ルイ史上いっぱいあるんだけど
Well, there are a lot of "firsts in history" this time...
鷹嶺ルイ史上初の、オリジナルアニメMV、フルアニメMVをね、作らせていただきました！
...but this is my very first original, full-animation MV!
すごかった、めっちゃぬるぬる動いてた。 / ぬるぬる動いてたでしょ？
That was amazing, the animation was so incredibly smooth. / Right? So smooth!
しかも、なんか、私が好きそうな絵のタッチじゃない？
Plus, doesn't the art style look like something I'd totally love?
あー、確かにね！
Ah, definitely!
なんと、私ですね、かねてよりMV作っていただきたいな、と思っていた、安田現象さんに！
Actually, it was made by Yasuda Gensho-san, whom I've wanted to make an MV for me for a very long time!
あの？！ / あの、安田現象さんに！
THAT one?! / Yes, THAT Yasuda Gensho-san!
あの安田現象さんですか？！ / そう、大丈夫ですか、大丈夫ですか？
THE Yasuda Gensho-san?! / Yes, are you okay? Are you okay?
はい。
Yes.
あの、安田現象さんに作成をしていただいたフルアニメーションMVとなっております。
This is a full-animation MV created by Yasuda Gensho.
わー、すごい。サムネもかわいい。
Wow, amazing. The thumbnail is cute too.
かわいいでしょ？
It's cute, right?
あっかんべーしてます。
It's sticking its tongue out.
あっかんべーしてるね。
It is sticking its tongue out, indeed.
ということでこのね『DARE!?』というのは、
So, about this song "DARE!?",
内面にいる、ま、私の…私は結構内面にアンチも持ってるんですけど。
it refers to the critic inside me... I actually have a critic inside me.
あ、そうなんだ。
Oh, is that so?
そう、鷹嶺ルイのアンチを持ってるんですけど。
Yes, a critic of Takane Lui.
「お前本当にこれでいいのか？」みたいなね。
Like, "Are you really okay with this?"
「お前本当にやれんのか？」みたいな。
Or "Can you actually do this?"
そ、え、このなんか感情って誰なん？みたいな。
And then, "Wait, whose feelings are these?"
あ、え、私なん？私なの？
"Is it me? Am I the one?"
なんで私は私を否定してるの？みたいな。
"Why am I denying myself?"
そういうね、深い…「誰？」っていう。
That kind of deep... "Who is it?" question.
そういう楽曲に仕上がっておりますし、それを…
That's the kind of song it is, and...
てか Who are you? って。
Like, "By the way, who are you?"
「誰？」
"Who?"
「誰なん？」
"Who is it?"
「誰なんの？私」みたいな。
Like, "Who am I?"
誰なの？
Who is it?
という、えー、曲になっておりますので、これからちょっとMVもね、
Since that's the theme of the song, we'll premiere the MV next.
あのプレミア公開させていただきますので、ぜひぜひ。
Please look forward to it.
楽しんでいただければなと思いますし、結構耳に残るサウンドになってますのでね。
It has a really catchy sound!
ね、もう今も後ろでインスト流れてますけど。
Yeah, the instrumental is playing in the background right now.
これ早くフル聞きたいし、もうなんなら今から歌ってもらえませんか？
I want to hear the full version soon, or could you sing it for us right now?
え、え、何、え、え、一緒に歌いますか？
Eh? What? Do you want to sing together?
え、え、あ、うーん、チャチャチャチャチャン、ヘイ、ヘイ。
Eh? Oh, well... cha-cha-cha-cha-chan, hey, hey.
ちょっと歌えなさそうですね。
Looks like you can't sing it.
ということでこの後、実は『DARE!?』を、先行で歌わせていただきます！
So, actually, right after this, I will be performing "DARE!?" early!
おー！そうなの？
Oh! Is that so?
じゃあ私は端から見ますということで。
Then, I'll watch from the side.
あ、待っててね、あの、ご飯食べ…ご飯食べよう一緒に。
Oh, wait for me, okay? Let's get some food together afterwards.
あ、わかったわかった。じゃあ舞台袖で見てますわ。
Ah, okay, okay. I'll watch from the wings.
この後じゃあご飯ということでよろしくお願いします。
We'll get food after this, thank you!
てか Who are you? 誰？ じゃ。
By the way, who are you? Who? Bye!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much!
すいちゃんでした！ありがとうみんなー、ありがとう！
That was Sui-chan! Thank you everyone, thank you!
ということで、えー心強かった助っ人すいちゃんもいなくなり、私一人でですね、
With that, my reassuring helper Sui-chan is gone, and I am here alone.
え、新曲ラピスラズリにも入っております曲、え、『DARE!?』を歌わせていただきます。
I will be singing "DARE!?", which is also included in my new album, "Lapis Lazuli".
ちょっと水飲んでいいですか？
Can I drink some water?
水飲みますよ、水飲みます。よいしょ。
I'm going to drink water. Here we go.
はい、ということで、戻ってまいりました。
Alright, I have returned.
それでは皆さん、聴いてください。ふぅー。『DARE!?』
Now everyone, please listen to... "DARE!?"
だれだ だれ？ そちら様 どちら様？ はてさてと
Who is it, who? Who are you? Let me see...
フーアーユー？ ハウアーユー？ お元気で 一足お先に
Who are you? How are you? I'll head on ahead.
てか フーアーユー？
I mean, who are you?
昨日のジブンが描いた円から はみ出さないように
Trying not to step out of the circle my past self drew,
ひとまわり小さな円を描くような
as if drawing a slightly smaller circle inside...
ボールのバウンドが少しずつ 低くなる様を
Like watching the bounce of a ball slowly diminish,
術もなく眺めているような気分でしょ？ アハ ところでアナタ
helplessly looking on, that's how you feel, right? Haha, by the way, who are you?
だれ？ だれ？ だれ？ だれ？ だれ？ だれ？
Who? Who? Who? Who? Who? Who?
おや はてさて 存じ上げないわ
Oh my, well, I have no idea who you are.
フーアーユー ユー ユー ユー どちら様？
Who are you, you, you, you? Who?
face to face コンニチハ ユーはミー？
Face to face, hello. Are you me?
もーなんてったって up side down for ジブン ジブン
I mean, after all, everything is upside down for myself.
look alike 雷雨 落雷 落下 落花 蕾 とおりゃんせ
Lookalike, thunderstorm, lightning, falling petals, passing through.
てかオマエ てかオマエ てかオマエはだれ！？
I mean, who are you!? Who are you!? Who are you!?
昨日のジブンはジブンの手で片付けましょう
Let's clean up yesterday's self with our own hands.
てか フーアーユー だれ！？
I mean, who are you, who!?
昼夜問わず私が私のこと見張り続けてる
Day and night, I keep watching over myself.
なのでグッと背筋伸ばし微笑むの キャハ
So I straighten my back and smile, haha!
花は誰に見られずとも美しく咲くというけど
They say flowers bloom beautifully even if no one watches,
風や虫にもそっぽ向かれたら咲き方を改めるだろう
but if even the wind and bugs ignore them, they'd change how they bloom, right?
だれ だれ？ だれ！？
Who, who? Who!?
存じ上げないわ だれ？
I have no idea who you are. Who?
フーアーユー ユー ユー ユー どちら様？
Who are you, you, you, you? Who?
face to face コンバンハ
Face to face, good evening.
ユーはミー？
Are you me?
もーなんてったって up side down for ジブン ジブン
I mean, after all, everything is upside down for myself.
look alike 雷雨 落雷 落下 落花 蕾 とおりゃんせ
Lookalike, thunderstorm, lightning, falling petals, passing through.
てかオマエ てかオマエ てかオマエはだれ！？
I mean, who are you!? Who are you!? Who are you!?
まいた　まいた　まいたのはだれ？
Who was the one who sowed it?
明日の私は私を倒せ
Tomorrow's me, defeat myself!
てか Who are you?
Anyway, who are you?
How are you?
How about you?
だれ！？
Who!?
look alike and...
look alike alike alike me!
だれだ　だれ？
Who's that? Who is it?
そちら様
Dear whomever,
どちら様？
which one are you?
はてさてと
Well, let's see...
これはだれだ？
Who is this?
だれであれ
No matter who it is,
見せつけるだけ
I'll just show off!
take a look my dare
have a nice dare
はい ということで 今日のライブはこれにて終了となります
All right! And with that, today's live concert has come to an end!
みなさん 本当にありがとうございました
Thank you all so very much!
改めて 告知をさせていただきます
Allow me to share the announcements once again!
セカンドアルバム「Lapis Lazuli」が12月3日に発売されます
My second album, Lapis Lazuli, will be released on December 3rd!
えー 予約は えー もうできますので こちらかな？
Um, pre-orders are... well, they're open now, so... is it over here?
こちらから ぜひぜひ予約をしてください
Please make sure to pre-order from this link!
もう すごく頑張った えー 楽曲 頑張って頑張って歌った楽曲ばかりになりますので
The album is packed with songs that I worked incredibly hard on, songs I sang with all my might...
ぜひぜひ早くみなさんに聴いていただきたいなと思いますので えー ぜひセカンドアルバムもよろしくお願いします
...so I really hope you can listen to them soon! Please look forward to the second album!
えー そして えー 豪華なスライドボックスパッケージで
And, um, it comes in a gorgeous slide-box package...
イラストブックや缶バッジ 直筆サイン入りのジャケットカードなどがついてくる完全生産限定盤
...with an art book, badges, a hand-signed jacket card, and more as the Complete Limited Edition!
えー そして ランダムアナザージャケット 全5種から1枚
Also, there's a random alternative jacket—one out of five types...
数量限定ランダムで直筆サインとメッセージがつく通常盤 えー 各種法人特典も盛りだくさんでございます
...and a limited Regular Edition which randomly includes a hand-signed autograph and message. Plus, plenty of store-exclusive benefits!
えー 秋葉原ゲーマーズ本店さんにてリリース記念の えー ミニライブもやる予定でございます
I'm also planning to hold a release commemoration mini-live at Gamers Akihabara Main Store!
デジタルシングル「dare!?」が本日24時にデジタルリリースされますし
Additionally, "dare!?", which I just performed, will be digitally released tonight at midnight...
このあとすぐフルアニメーションも MV公開されます
...and right after this, the full animation music video will be released!
えー このままね 見ていただければ えー 自動で
If you stay tuned and keep watching, um, it should automatically...
確か 確か自動で MVに飛びますので
I think... I'm pretty sure it automatically transitions to the MV...
ぜひぜひフルアニメーション あの 私自身初のフルアニメーションになっておりますので
...so please watch it! It's my very first full-animation music video!
ぜひ 可愛く仕上がったので見ていただけると嬉しいでございます
It turned out so cute, so I'd be absolutely thrilled if you watched it!
はい
Yes!
えー 今回あの 重大告知ライブということで みなさんね
Since this is a "Major Announcement Stream", many of you...
あの「ソロライブなんじゃないか？」って すごい あの 予想してくださっていたんですけれども
...were probably speculating and hoping for a solo live concert.
私はですね まだあの ソロライブは あの 決まっておりません
But actually, my solo live concert has not been decided yet!
ですが ですね 私あの 音楽をやりたいと えー 心に決めてからですね
However, ever since I made up my mind to pursue music seriously...
えー 夢であるファーストアルバムがリリースできたり
...I was able to fulfill my dream of releasing my first album...
そしてファーストアルバムをみなさんが 買ってくださったから
...and because you all bought that first album...
えー こうやってセカンドアルバムを全国流通として えー 発売することができました
...I am now able to release my second album with nationwide distribution.
えー 1000万回再生のMVを えー が2つも えー できましたし
We also reached 10 million views on two of my music videos!
そのほかの楽曲も たくさんたくさんみんなに愛してもらって えー 再生数もすごい伸びて
My other songs have also received so much love, racking up incredible view counts.
もう みんなのおかげでですね 私 あの こんなに あの 音楽をやっていてよかったなと
It is truly thanks to all of you that I feel so glad to be doing music.
今でも えー そしてこれからもきっと 思うと思います
I feel that way now, and I'm sure I always will.
えー ソロライブ 次はですね えー 夢を1つずつ叶えてきたからこそ
For a solo live... Since we've been making my dreams come true one by one...
次は もう ソロライブしかないやろ！
...the next step has to be a solo live concert, right?
なので えー 必ず えー みなさまと一緒にソロライブを えー 夢見て
So I want us to keep dreaming of that solo live together...
みんなと一緒にまたここから走り出したいなと思います
...and start running towards it from this very moment!
えー ぜひぜひ みなさん えー ファーストに引き続きセカンドアルバムも
So following the first one, please get your hands on the second album...
お手元にとって頂けると嬉しいです
...I'd be so happy if you did.
なので えー これから また高嶺ルイと一緒にソロライブを
So from here on out, let's keep aiming for that solo live...
目指しましょう
...with Takane Lui!
目指してくれますか？
Will you aim for it with me?
ん？
Hmm?
ん？目指してくれるか？
Hmm? Will you?
もちろん え ありがとう
"Of course"? Ah, thank you!
はい もう本当にみんなの えー 力がないと 私は えー
Yes, without everyone's support, I...
きっとソロライブに えー 到達できないと思うので
...definitely won't be able to reach that solo live concert.
私も頑張りますが みんなも一緒に走り続けて頂けると嬉しいです
I will do my best, so I'd be so happy if you keep running alongside me!
えー ルイ友のみんな そして ルイのことは まあ 2番手3番手くらいに推しているよというみんな
To all the Lui-tomo, and even those who support me as their second or third favorite!
アンド ホロリスのみんな そして これからまた出会うであろう
To all the Hololistic fans, and to everyone I have yet to meet...
えー 高嶺ルイを知っていただけるみなさん
...who will get to know Takane Lui in the future...
みなさんの協力が必要ですので ぜひ！
...I need your support, so please!
ぜひ、これからも鷹嶺ルイをよろしくお願いします！
Please continue to support Takane Lui!
はい、ということで、じゃあ次のね...
All right, with that said, next...
ま、次重大告知があるときには、もう
The next time there's a major announcement,
超重大告知としてね
it'll be a super major announcement,
そのライブが発表できるように、これからもがんばります！
I'll keep doing my best so I can announce that concert!
みんな、本当に今日はありがとうー！
Thank you so much for today, everyone!
セカンドアルバム楽しみにしててね
Please look forward to the second album.
これからどんどん情報が出てくると思いますので
More and more information will be released,
お楽しみに！
so please look forward to it!
またねー！
See you!